Guide to the Vassar-Yale Joint Study Group, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Vassar-Yale Joint Study Group, Yale University, records
1963-1968
RU 526
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(11 boxes)
The records consist of committee reports, drafts, and research materials documenting the activities and operations of the Vassar-Yale Joint Study Group, which was formed to study the possible merger between Vassar College and Yale University.
Yale University. Vassar-Yale Joint Study Group
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of committee reports, drafts, and research materials documenting the activities and operations of the Vassar-Yale Joint Study Group, which was formed to study the possible merger between Vassar College and Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Coeducation; Universities and colleges -- Mergers; Vassar College; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Vassar-Yale Joint Study Group
- Reports and research materials, 1963-1968; Accession 1973-A-004
  - Accreditation Re-evaluation
    - Committees, guidelines, schedules, and general information, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Accreditation Report
    - Final draft for clerical office, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - For New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Working copy, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Accreditation Study
    - Programs of study in Yale College and Graduate School, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9 - 10)
    - Administration, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11 - 13)
  - Administrative departments, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Admissions data - Yale and Vassar, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Architects and engineers-requests for job consideration, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Athletic facilities and activities, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 17 - 18)
  - Budget
    - Account statements, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Charges included in official monthly account statement, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21 - 23)
    - Petty cash account, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Building facilities-Vassar, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Buildings and grounds-Yale inventory, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 26 - 27)
  - Comparative charts, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Cooperative proposals without relocation, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Corporation action re: coeducation, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence
    - Re: Vassar/Yale affiliation, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 31 - 32)
    - With Carnegie Corporation, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - With Vassar, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - With Yale, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Degree requirements-Vassar, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Department Chairman guidelines, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Departmental meetings-Vassar/Yale representatives' reports, 1967
    - A-B, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - C-F, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - G-L, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - M-Pn, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Po-R, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - S-Z, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Departmental reports, 1967
    - Final copies
      - A-Q (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - R-Z (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Yale Pilot Departments-for meeting May 15 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Enrollment
    - Vassar-by departments, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Yale
      - By departments, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 48 - 49)
      - Count by division
        - 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 50)
        - 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Enrollment sheets-Yale, 1966-1967
    - Fall term (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Spring term (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Faculty data, 1966-1967
    - Vassar (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Yale (Box 7, Folder 55 - 56)
  - Guidelines for Vassar/Yale study, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Inter-related institutions - articles and reports, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 58 - 60)
  - Land-Day Prospect Hill School, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Language Laboratory report, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Library-report, newsletters, and budget, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Lieberman reports re: coordinate colleges, site for Vassar in New Haven, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Mailing lists and addresses for Vassar/Yale reports-staff and trustees, undated (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Meeting of Vassar/Yale study group staffs - Agenda, reports, and associated correspondence, 1967
    - Jan (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Feb-Mar (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Apr 13 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Apr 21 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - May (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Jun-Aug (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Minutes of joint staff meetings, 1967 January-June (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Personnel, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Preliminary report
    - Draft, 1967
      - Jul 5, 14 (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - Jul 27 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Aug 12 (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Aug 29-30 (Box 9, Folder 77)
      - Sep (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Final draft, 1967 September (Box 9, Folder 79 - 80)
    - Final form for clerical office, 1967 September (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Official version for trustees, 1967 September (Box 10, Folder 82 - 83)
    - Printed version, 1967 September (Box 10, Folder 84 - 85)
  - Press releases and public statements, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Reports on progress of study, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Residential colleges-a joint report of the Student Advisory Board, undated (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Vassar bulletins and handbooks, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Vassar wives of Yale alumni mailing lists, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 90)
- Records, 1967-1968; Accession 2014-A-040
  - Correspondence
    - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Joint trustee-fellow meeting, 1967 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Site planning, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Trustees statement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)